<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nomasters</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on nomasters</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 08:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>goodbye keybase</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/quitting-keybase/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/quitting-keybase/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s long overdue, but I&amp;rsquo;m quitting &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/&#34;&gt;keybase&lt;/a&gt; and deleting my account. After the TLS issues today, it was a stark reminder that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.zoom.us/zoom-acquires-keybase-and-announces-goal-of-developing-the-most-broadly-used-enterprise-end-to-end-encryption-offering/&#34;&gt;Zoom acquisition&lt;/a&gt; effectively killed keybase &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/keybase/client/graphs/contributors&#34;&gt;long ago&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/rjrbt&#34;&gt;https://keybase.io/rjrbt&lt;/a&gt; is no more.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in communicating with me, you can find an email address to kick off communication at &lt;a href=&#34;https://n.2p5.xyz/&#34;&gt;https://n.2p5.xyz/&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve also got a &lt;a href=&#34;https://signal.org/en/&#34;&gt;signal&lt;/a&gt; account, but you&amp;rsquo;ll have to ask for that number :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>functionally imperative</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/functionally-imperative/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 09:23:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/functionally-imperative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share that I&amp;rsquo;ve released my first video &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iyN1upBxbMw&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;cgi-bin, ftw (part 1)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; for a new project I&amp;rsquo;ve started called: &lt;a href=&#34;https://funcimp.biz/&#34;&gt;functionally imperative&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of little project ideas floating around in my head for a while. Over the last few months I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://bettertogether.group/&#34;&gt;Better Together&lt;/a&gt; to dive in deeper and help me reach clarity on my goals and my process for accomplishing these goals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Expect to see more writing here as well: I just finished reading Seth Godin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/53479927-the-practice&#34;&gt;The Practice&lt;/a&gt; (highly recommended). It has inspired me to commit to the practice of creation again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>gravity wells</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gravity-wells/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 03:03:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gravity-wells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those who do not move, do not notice their chains.&#xA;&amp;ndash; Rosa Luxemburg&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gravity_well&#34;&gt;gravity wells&lt;/a&gt;. There is something beautiful that emerges from a conceptual model that takes an opaque concept and puts it into intuitive terms. So, at risk of pushing a metaphor too far, I&amp;rsquo;ve been entertaining a whimsical thought experiment about how we interact and engage with the world around us. Though I&amp;rsquo;m genuine in my effort, I ask you not to take any of this too seriously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>handshake: a peculiar chat experiment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/handshake-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 21:26:27 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/handshake-alpha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share an early prototype of a strange chat experiment that I&amp;rsquo;ve been quietly &lt;del&gt;obsessing over&lt;/del&gt; working on. I&amp;rsquo;m calling it &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nomasters/handshake&#34;&gt;handshake&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Handshake is designed to be an experiment in one-time key symmetric cryptography. The tool is based on off-line and in-person initialization of communication so that all future transmissions rely exclusively on pre-shared one-time symmetric key cryptography. This is primarily a design for out-of-band communication in which communicating parties aim to mitigate potential compromises in asymmetric encryption methodology ranging from CA poisoning to reliance on trusted centralized service providers for communications technology, and it can even be used to explore patterns in post-quantum readiness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sxsw 2019</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sxsw-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 15:21:06 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sxsw-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be in the US in March attending &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sxsw.com/&#34;&gt;sxsw 2019&lt;/a&gt; as a &lt;a href=&#34;http://schedule.sxsw.com/2019/events/PP100992&#34;&gt;mentor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re going, &lt;a href=&#34;https://keybase.io/rjrbt/&#34;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll see you at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/EFF-Austin/events/258945670/&#34;&gt;EFF party&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>meaning-less-ness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/meaning-less-ness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 23:15:49 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/meaning-less-ness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emergence&#34;&gt;emergence&lt;/a&gt; lately. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/crypto&#34;&gt;online cryptography class&lt;/a&gt; I recently completed, the ideas in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/695429.G_del_s_Proof?from_search=true&#34;&gt;Godel&amp;rsquo;s Proof&lt;/a&gt; still fresh in my mind, or recently diving deeper into trying to understand &lt;a href=&#34;https://eater.net/quaternions&#34;&gt;quaternions&lt;/a&gt;, but I’ve been dwelling on thoughts about the emergence of meaning from seeming meaningless-ness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What do I mean by this? Well, I’m not really interested in getting into a philosophical debate about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emergence#Strong_and_weak_emergence&#34;&gt;strong emergence&lt;/a&gt; or the specifics of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reductionism&#34;&gt;reductionism&lt;/a&gt;. I want to explore some anecdotes, and possibly a thought experiment or two on that peculiar thing we call the mind and a strange thing it seems to be concerned with: meaning. I’m more specifically speaking of emergence in the sense that emergent properties are those that seem to exist outside of the raw sum of the parts themselves. Be warned: this is a layman&amp;rsquo;s exploration of this topic. These are some ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve scrounged together and that I&amp;rsquo;ve had fun thinking about. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are holes in the logic, and I&amp;rsquo;m making no claim to how the universe actually works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>on avoiding boredom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-avoiding-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/on-avoiding-boredom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Boring is an attitude, not the truth. Possibility is where you decide it is.&#xA;&amp;ndash; Seth Godin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I think we, as humans, have a natural inclination to want to avoid boredom. And it&amp;rsquo;s easier now than ever to reach for the dopamine-infused mental junk food in an attempt to satiate our desires. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to resist when corporations pour endless amounts of money into building games, apps, platforms, and media by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.1843magazine.com/features/the-scientists-who-make-apps-addictive&#34;&gt;hiring scientists to create systems to modify our behavior and trigger addiction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>meditations on authority</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/meditations-on-authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 07:30:05 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/meditations-on-authority/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That is what I have always understood to be the essence of anarchism: the conviction that the burden of proof has to be placed on authority, and that it should be dismantled if that burden cannot be met.&#xA;&amp;ndash; Noam Chomsky&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was eleven when I stopped believing in god. I have a vivid memory of the feeling. It was existentially disorienting. It was like I had stopped clinging to the side of a cliff and I was in free-fall. If there was no god, who was in charge? It was as though I&amp;rsquo;d uncovered a deep secret that no one around me talked about. It was something I&amp;rsquo;d kept to myself for a long time. I grew up in the Deep South and though my immediate family wasn&amp;rsquo;t particularly religious (though we did attend church every Sunday), my extended family and the community at large certainly were.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>unquantified</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/unquantified/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 09:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/unquantified/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The only real valuable thing is intuition.&#xA;&amp;ndash; Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A year ago I got rid of my scale, a simple act that turned out to be the catalyst for a year&amp;rsquo;s worth of quiet introspection and experimentation in removing quantification from my life. A year later I&amp;rsquo;m quantifiably more ignorant about myself than I have been in more than a decade, but I&amp;rsquo;m far more in tune with my intuition, which has cultivated a deeper understanding of my well-being. I have come to the conclusion that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantified_self&#34;&gt;quantified self&lt;/a&gt; is a misguided movement and that it isn&amp;rsquo;t one worth pursuing. For me, it represents a simulacrum of introspection. It&amp;rsquo;s as if I&amp;rsquo;d decided that I wanted to go on an adventure through the Grand Canyon, but instead of traveling there and truly experiencing it, I obsessed over creating the perfect map of the Grand Canyon and stared at it endlessly while going through the paces, never looking up to experience the true beauty of being there in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>dumber phone</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dumber-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 17:05:19 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dumber-phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Less is exponentially more&#xA;&amp;ndash; Rob Pike&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Smart phones are useful, but they are also &lt;a href=&#34;https://edition.cnn.com/2017/11/30/health/smartphone-addiction-study/index.html&#34;&gt;incredibly addictive&lt;/a&gt;, and that addiction is at the epicenter of Silicon Valley&amp;rsquo;s effort to grab an ever-increasing percentage of our minds. If a substance or behavior controls us, it becomes our master, and that just won&amp;rsquo;t do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the humor of it, let&amp;rsquo;s use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.webmd.com/mental-health/addiction/signs-of-drug-addiction#1&#34;&gt;this webMD post&lt;/a&gt; and only slightly modify the key signature behaviors outlined to describe smart phone usage addiction:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>killcord alpha</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/killcord-alpha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/killcord-alpha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past four months, I&amp;rsquo;ve been quietly working on a project that I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to share. It&amp;rsquo;s still in its very early alpha phase and needs a healthy dose of vetting, testing, and refactoring, but I&amp;rsquo;m proud of the initial implementation and it&amp;rsquo;s a starting point for an open source project that I&amp;rsquo;m excited to work on.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-background&#34;&gt;the background&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d started casually diving into the technology behind &lt;a href=&#34;https://solidity.readthedocs.io/en/develop/introduction-to-smart-contracts.html&#34;&gt;Ethereum smart contracts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://ipfs.io/&#34;&gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt;. I started wondering: if Ethereum can run unstoppable and decentralized code and IPFS can create undeletable storage on the network, could I build a censorship-resistant &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dead_man%27s_switch&#34;&gt;deadman&amp;rsquo;s switch&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nonparticipation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nonparticipation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 11:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nonparticipation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve attempted to live on first principles, one of the most powerful tools at my disposal has been the ability to opt out of participating in systems that I feel are harmful, unjust, induce deep skepticism, or give power to those who I feel gain such power undeservedly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nonparticipation is a powerful and transformative tool. It is a pillar of self-governance. Exploring this principle has had a transformative effect in my life. This idea is so powerful, in fact, that it can seem a bit bewildering in its simplicity. The power in nonparticipation hides in the fact that power relies on participation. If you choose to not participate, you choose to not give power to those who mean to take it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sans copyright</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sans-copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 09:41:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sans-copyright/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anything that prevents you from being friendly, a good neighbor, is a terror tactic.&#xA;&amp;ndash; Richard Stallman&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You might have noticed this site is &lt;a href=&#34;https://nomasters.io/uncopyright/&#34;&gt;uncopyrighted&lt;/a&gt;, and I thought I&amp;rsquo;d explore a bit my reasoning behind my decision and the underlying principles that brought me to declare that all content on this site is in the public domain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The modern concept of intellectual property is puzzlingly complex. The topic operates on certain assumptions about human nature, innovation, and the role of the state in the market that I feel are worth questioning, and, if you are willing to follow me down the rabbit hole, ones worth opting out of.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>uncopyright</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/uncopyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:10:45 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/uncopyright/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://mnmlist.com/uncopyright/&#34;&gt;license from mnmlist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This site exists without copyrights. Its creator has released all claims on copyright and has &lt;strong&gt;put all the content into the public domain.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;No permission is needed to copy, distribute, or modify the content of this site. Credit is appreciated but not required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terms and Conditions for Copying, Distribution, and Modification:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do whatever you like.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the beginning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 15:26:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-beginning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this project is to capture my &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/&#34;&gt;thoughts&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nomasters&#34;&gt;work&lt;/a&gt; on a journey towards living in accordance to a set of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_principle&#34;&gt;first principles&lt;/a&gt; revolving around &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freethought&#34;&gt;freethought&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skepticism&#34;&gt;skepticism&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Libertarian_socialism&#34;&gt;libertarian socialism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Because of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://n.2p5.xyz/&#34;&gt;work as a technologist&lt;/a&gt;, this project will tend to cover topics that are technical in nature, but also explore guiding principles as they relate to the focus of this project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anything published by this project exists in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_domain&#34;&gt;public domain&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Content written for this project uses the &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/uncopyright&#34;&gt;uncopyright&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Code written for this project uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unlicense&#34;&gt;unlicense&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
